Guide to the James E. Jackson and Esther Cooper Jackson Papers TAM 347
Tamiment Library / Wagner Archives
- Series IV: Correspondence.
  - Subseries IV:A: Chronological Correspondence.
    - Correspondence, Chronological, 1948 (Box 3, Folder 23)
    - Correspondence, Chronological, 1950 (Box 3, Folder 24)
    - Correspondence, Chronological, 1951 (Box 3, Folder 25)
    - Correspondence, Chronological, 1952 (Box 3, Folder 26)
    - Correspondence, Chronological, 1953 (Box 3, Folder 27)
    - Correspondence, Chronological, 1954 (Box 3, Folder 28)
    - Correspondence, Chronological, 1955 (Box 3, Folder 29)
    - Correspondence, Chronological, 1956 (Box 3, Folder 30)
    - Correspondence, Chronological, 1957 (Box 3, Folder 31)
    - Correspondence, Chronological, 1958 (Box 3, Folder 32)
    - Correspondence, Chronological, 1959 (Box 3, Folder 33)
    - Correspondence, Chronological, 1960 (Box 3, Folder 34)
    - Correspondence, Chronological, 1961 (Box 3, Folder 35)
    - Correspondence, Chronological, 1962 (Box 3, Folder 36)
    - Correspondence, Chronological, 1963 (Box 3, Folder 37)
    - Correspondence, Chronological, 1964 (Box 3, Folder 38)
    - Correspondence, Chronological, 1965 (Box 3, Folder 39)
    - Correspondence, Chronological, 1966 (Box 3, Folder 40)
    - Correspondence, Chronological, 1967 (Box 3, Folder 41)
    - Correspondence, Chronological, 1968 (Box 3, Folder 42)
    - Correspondence, Chronological, 1969 (Box 3, Folder 43)
    - Correspondence, Chronological, 1970 (Box 4, Folder 1)
    - Correspondence, Chronological, 1971 (Box 4, Folder 2)
    - Correspondence, Chronological, 1972 (Box 4, Folder 3)
    - Correspondence, Chronological, 1973 (Box 4, Folder 4)
    - Correspondence, Chronological, 1974 (Box 4, Folder 5)
    - Correspondence, Chronological, 1975 (Box 4, Folder 6)
    - Correspondence, Chronological, 1976 (Box 4, Folder 7)
    - Correspondence, Chronological, 1977 (Box 4, Folder 8)
    - Correspondence, Chronological, 1978 (Box 4, Folder 9)
    - Correspondence, Chronological, 1979 (Box 4, Folder 10)
    - Correspondence, Chronological, 1980 (Box 4, Folder 11)
    - Correspondence, Chronological, 1981 (Box 4, Folder 12)
    - Correspondence, Chronological, 1982 (Box 4, Folder 13)
    - Correspondence, Chronological, 1983 (Box 4, Folder 14)
    - Correspondence, Chronological, 1984 (Box 4, Folder 15)
    - Correspondence, Chronological, 1985 (Box 4, Folder 16)
    - Correspondence, Chronological, 1986 (Box 4, Folder 17)
    - Correspondence, Chronological, 1987 (Box 4, Folder 18)
    - Correspondence, Chronological, 1988 (Box 4, Folder 19)
    - Correspondence, Chronological, 1989 (Box 5, Folder 1)
    - Correspondence, Chronological, 1990 (Box 5, Folder 2)
    - Correspondence, Chronological, 1991 (Box 5, Folder 3)
    - Correspondence, Chronological, 1992 (Box 5, Folder 4)
    - Correspondence, Chronological, 1993 (Box 5, Folder 5)
    - Correspondence, Chronological, 1994 (Box 5, Folder 6)
    - Correspondence, Chronological, 1995 (Box 5, Folder 7)
    - Correspondence, Chronological, 1996 (Box 5, Folder 8)
    - Correspondence, Chronological, 1997 (Box 5, Folder 9)
    - Correspondence, Chronological, 1998 (Box 5, Folder 10)
    - Correspondence, Chronological, 1999 (Box 5, Folder 11)
    - Correspondence, Chronological, 2000 (Box 5, Folder 12)
    - Correspondence, Chronological, 2001 (Box 5, Folder 13)
    - Correspondence, Chronological, 2002 (Box 5, Folder 14)
    - Correspondence, Chronological, 2003 (Box 5, Folder 15)
    - Correspondence, Chronological, 2004 (Box 5, Folder 16)
  - Subseries IV:B: Alphabetical Correspondence.
    - Correspondence, Alphabetical: A - B, Undated (Box 5, Folder 17)
    - Correspondence, Alphabetical: Bloice, Carl, 1982-1992 (Box 5, Folder 18)
    - Correspondence, Alphabetical: C - D, Undated (Box 5, Folder 19)
    - Correspondence, Alphabetical: Castro, Fidel - letters to, 1961-1968 (Box 5, Folder 20)
    - Correspondence, Alphabetical: Chandra, Romesh, Undated (Box 5, Folder 21)
    - Correspondence, Alphabetical: Davis, Ben, 1955 (Box 5, Folder 22)
    - Correspondence, Alphabetical: Dennis, Gene, 1965 (Box 5, Folder 23)
    - Correspondence, Alphabetical: Dennis, Peggy, 1963-1967 (Box 5, Folder 24)
    - Correspondence, Alphabetical: Du Bois, W.E.B., 1961-1963 (Box 5, Folder 25)
    - Correspondence: Alphabetical: Du Bois, W.E.B., Applying for Membership in the CPUSA, 1961 (Box 5, Folder 26)
    - Correspondence: Alphabetical: E - H, Undated (Box 5, Folder 27)
    - Correspondence: Alphabetical: Evans (re: Sale of Ollie Harrington Drawings), 1991 (Box 5, Folder 28)
    - Correspondence: Alphabetical: Foster, William Z., 1960 (Box 5, Folder 29)
    - Correspondence: Alphabetical: Gerson, Simon, 1981-1993 (Box 5, Folder 30)
    - Correspondence: Alphabetical: Gorbachev, Mikhail (Letter to), 1991 (Box 5, Folder 31)
    - Correspondence: Alphabetical: Hall, Gus, Undated (Box 5, Folder 32)
    - Correspondence: Alphabetical: Harrington, Ollie, 1977-1993, Undated (Box 5, Folder 33)
    - Correspondence: Alphabetical: Hudson, Hosea, 1980-1986 (Box 5, Folder 34)
    - Correspondence: Alphabetical: I - J, Undated (Box 5, Folder 35)
    - Correspondence: Alphabetical: Jackson, Rev. Jesse, 1983 (Box 5, Folder 36)
    - Correspondence: Alphabetical: K - L, Undated (Box 5, Folder 37)
    - Correspondence: Alphabetical: M - O, Undated (Box 5, Folder 38)
    - Correspondence: Alphabetical: Murphy, George (re: "Black Delegation Visits the USSR"), 1972 (Box 5, Folder 39)
    - Correspondence: Alphabetical: Neruda, Pablo, 1966-1967 (Box 5, Folder 40)
    - Correspondence: Alphabetical: P - S, Undated (Box 5, Folder 41)
    - Correspondence: Alphabetical: Pittman, John, 1966-1984 (Box 5, Folder 42)
    - Correspondence: Alphabetical: "Pharmacy", 1969-1970 (Box 5, Folder 43)
    - Correspondence: Alphabetical: Retirement Dispute, 1992 (Box 5, Folder 44)
    - Correspondence: Alphabetical: Strong, Ed, 1936 (Box 5, Folder 45)
    - Correspondence: Alphabetical: T - Z, Undated (Box 5, Folder 46)
    - Correspondence: Alphabetical: West, Jim, Undated (Box 5, Folder 47)
    - Correspondence: Alphabetical: Winston, Henry, 1961-1986 (Box 5, Folder 48)
    - Correspondence: Alphabetical: Winter, Carl, 1956-1957, 1990 (Box 5, Folder 49)
  - Subseries IV:C: Third Party Correspondence.
    - Correspondence, Third Party: A - E, 1966-1997 (Box 6, Folder 1)
    - Correspondence, Third Party: Azikiwe, Nnamdi, 1965 (Box 6, Folder 2)
    - Correspondence, Third Party: Chandra, Romesh, 1988 (Box 6, Folder 3)
    - Correspondence, Third Party: Davis, Angela, Undated (Box 6, Folder 4)
    - Correspondence, Third Party: Du Bois, W.E.B., 1961 (Box 6, Folder 5)
    - Correspondence, Third Party: F - K, 1957-1996 (Box 6, Folder 6)
    - Correspondence, Third Party: Hall, Gus, 1971-1983 (Box 6, Folder 7)
    - Correspondence, Third Party: Harrington, Ollie, 1990 (Box 6, Folder 8)
    - Correspondence, Third Party: Hudson, Hosea, 1981 (Box 6, Folder 9)
    - Correspondence, Third Party: Jackson, Daniel, 1968 (Box 6, Folder 10)
    - Correspondence, Third Party: L - R, 1960-1996 (Box 6, Folder 11)
    - Correspondence, Third Party: Pittman, John, 1959, 1978 (Box 6, Folder 12)
    - Correspondence, Third Party: S - Z, 1968-1991 (Box 6, Folder 13)
    - Correspondence, Third Party: Williams, Robert F., Letter to Fidel Castro, 1966 (Box 6, Folder 14)
    - Correspondence, Third Party: Winston, Henry, 1962-1986 (Box 6, Folder 15)
- Series V: Correspondence: Army Letters.
  - Burnham, Louis and Dorothy to James E. Jackson, 1943-1945 (Box 6, Folder 16)
  - Clippings, 1944-1945 (Box 6, Folder 17)
  - Jackson, Esther Cooper to James E. Jackson, Undated (Box 6, Folder 18)
  - Jackson, Esther Cooper to James E. Jackson, 1943 (Box 6, Folder 19)
  - Jackson, Esther Cooper to James E. Jackson, Jan 1944-Aug 1944 (Box 6, Folder 20)
  - Jackson, Esther Cooper to James E. Jackson, Sep 1944-Dec 1944 (Box 6, Folder 21)
  - Jackson, Esther Cooper to James E. Jackson, Jan 1945-Feb 1945 (Box 6, Folder 22)
  - Jackson, Esther Cooper to James E. Jackson, Mar 1945-Apr 1945 (Box 6, Folder 23)
  - Jackson, Esther Cooper to James E. Jackson, May 1945-Jun 1945 (Box 6, Folder 24)
  - Jackson, Esther Cooper to James E. Jackson, Jul 1945-Aug 1945 (Box 6, Folder 25)
  - Jackson, Esther Cooper to James E. Jackson, 1946 (Box 6, Folder 26)
  - Jackson, James E. to Esther Cooper Jackson, Undated (Box 6, Folder 27)
  - Jackson, James E. to Esther Cooper Jackson, 1943 (Box 6, Folder 28)
  - Jackson, James E. to Esther Cooper Jackson, 1944 (Box 6, Folder 29)
  - Jackson, James E. to Esther Cooper Jackson, Jan 1994-Feb 1944 (Box 6, Folder 30)
  - Jackson, James E. to Esther Cooper Jackson, Mar 1994-Apr 1944 (Box 6, Folder 31)
  - Jackson, James E. to Esther Cooper Jackson, May 1944-Jun 1944 (Box 6, Folder 32)
  - Jackson, James E. to Esther Cooper Jackson, Jul 1994-Aug 1944 (Box 6, Folder 33)
  - Jackson, James E. to Esther Cooper Jackson, Sep 1944-Oct 1944 (Box 6, Folder 34)
  - Jackson, James E. to Esther Cooper Jackson, Nov 1944-Dec 1944 (Box 6, Folder 35)
  - Jackson, James E. to Esther Cooper Jackson, Jan 1945 (Box 6, Folder 36)
  - Jackson, James E. to Esther Cooper Jackson, Feb 1945 (Box 6, Folder 37)
  - Jackson, James E. to Esther Cooper Jackson, Mar 1945 (Box 6, Folder 38)
  - Jackson, James E. to Esther Cooper Jackson, Apr 1945 (Box 6, Folder 39)
  - Jackson, James E. to Esther Cooper Jackson, May 1945 (Box 6, Folder 40)
  - Jackson, James E. to Esther Cooper Jackson, Jun 1945 (Box 6, Folder 41)
  - Jackson, James E. to Esther Cooper Jackson, Jul 1945 (Box 6, Folder 42)
  - Jackson, James E. to Esther Cooper Jackson, Aug 1945 (Box 6, Folder 43)
  - Jackson, James E. to Esther Cooper Jackson, Sep 1945 (Box 6, Folder 44)
  - Jackson, James E. to Esther Cooper Jackson, Oct-45-Jan-46 (Box 6, Folder 45)
  - Jackson, James E. to Family, 1943-1945 (Box 6, Folder 46)
  - Jackson, James E. Sr. to James E. Jackson, 1943-1945 (Box 6, Folder 47)
- Series VI: Freedomways (Esther Cooper Jackson)
  - Brochures, Flyers, Greeting Cards, 1963-1986 (Box 6, Folder 48)
  - Clippings, 1956-1981 (Box 6, Folder 49)
  - Contributors, 1963-1986 (Box 6, Folder 50)
  - Copyright Registrations, 1981-1986 (Box 6, Folder 51)
  - Correspondence: Chronological - Undated (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence: Chronological Folder 1., 1961-1975 (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence: Chronological Folder 2., 1976-1985 (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence: Chronological Folder 3., 1986-1999 (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence: Administrative, 1961-1986 (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence: Brown, Lloyd, 1978, 1982 (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence: Burnham, Dorothy, 1967, 1986 (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence: Conyers, John, 1969 (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - Correspondence: Davis, Ossie, 1984 (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - Correspondence: Dee, Ruby, 1970-1984 (Box 7, Folder 10)
  - Correspondence: Du Bois, Shirley Graham, 1961-1967 (Box 7, Folder 11)
  - Correspondence: Du Bois, Peck W. (Dr. W.E.B. DuBois' grandson), 1968 (Box 7, Folder 12)
  - Correspondence: Durr, Virginia, 1967 (Box 7, Folder 13)
  - Correspondence: Ellison, Ralph, 1964 (Box 7, Folder 14)
  - Correspondence: Harrington, Ollie, Undated (Box 7, Folder 15)
  - Correspondence: Pittman, John, 1978 (Box 7, Folder 16)
  - Correspondence: Robeson, Paul Jr., 1978 (Box 7, Folder 17)
  - Correspondence: Seven Seas Books (Berlin), 1976-1982 (Box 7, Folder 18)
  - Correspondence: Small, Charles, 1973 (Box 7, Folder 19)
  - Correspondence: Young, Coleman, 1968 (Box 7, Folder 20)
  - Events and Promotions, 1962-1993 (Box 7, Folder 21)
  - Financial Reports, 1974, 1980, 1984 (Box 7, Folder 22)
  - Friends of Freedomways, 1986 (Box 7, Folder 23)
  - Freedomways Festival of the Arts, 1976 (Box 7, Folder 24)
  - Freedomways Reader, 1964-2000 (Box 7, Folder 25)
  - Freedomways Reprints, 1961, 1967, 1970 (Box 7, Folder 26)
  - Guest Books, 1974-1986 (Box 7, Folder 27)
  - Guest Book, 1979-1986 (Box 7, Folder 28)
  - Kaiser, Ernest: In Defense of People's Black and White History and Culture(reprint), 1970 (Box 7, Folder 29)
  - Leases, 1981-1985 (Box 7, Folder 30)
  - Loans, 1976, 1984 (Box 7, Folder 31)
  - Media Issue, Undated (Box 7, Folder 32)
  - Paul Robeson Issue, 1970-1971 (Box 7, Folder 33)
  - Paul Robeson Souvenir Book, Undated (Box 7, Folder 34)
  - Paul Robeson: The Great Forerunner, 1977-1980 (Box 7, Folder 35)
  - Southern Freedom Movement - Grant Proposal, Undated (Box 7, Folder 36)
  - Submissions, Undated (Box 7, Folder 37)
  - Subscribers' Addresses, Undated (Box 7, Folder 38)
  - Tax Certificate, 1961 (Box 7, Folder 39)
  - Third Party Writings ( Freedomways Related), 1963- c.2000 (Box 7, Folder 40)
  - W.E.B. Du Bois Centennial Tribute, 1967-1972 (Box 7, Folder 41)
  - W.E.B. Du Bois Commemoration, Town Hall, Feb 1969 (Box 7, Folder 42)
  - W.E.B. Du Bois Sponsorship Reply Cards for Memorial at Carnegie Hall and Centennial Tribute, 1968-1969 (Box 7, Folder 43)
- Series VII: Esther Cooper Jackson Papers.
  - Subseries VII:A: Correspondence.
    - Correspondence: Chronological 1., 1952-1997, Undated (Box 7, Folder 44)
    - Correspondence: Chronological 2., 1998-2003 (Box 7, Folder 45)
    - Correspondence: Academia, 1974, 1984-1997 (Box 8, Folder 1)
    - Correspondence: Academia, 1998-2004 (Box 8, Folder 2)
    - Correspondence: Academia / Eric McDuffie, 1998-2004 (Box 8, Folder 3)
    - Correspondence: Brown, Lloyd, 1982, 1997-1998 (Box 8, Folder 4)
    - Correspondence: Burnham, Dorothy and Margaret Ann, 1966, 1970, 1982-1984 (Box 8, Folder 5)
    - Correspondence: Cole, Lester, 1983 (Box 8, Folder 6)
    - Correspondence: Cards, 1946, 1961-2004 (Box 8, Folder 7)
    - Correspondence: Davis, Benjamin D., Undated (Box 8, Folder 8)
    - Correspondence: Davis, Ossie and Dee, Ruby, 1961, 1988, 1998 (Box 8, Folder 9)
    - Correspondence: Duberman, Martin, 1982-1983 (Box 8, Folder 10)
    - Correspondence: Du Bois, Shirley Graham, 1960-1975 (Box 8, Folder 11)
    - Correspondence: Du Bois, W.E.B., 1945-1947, 1962 (Box 8, Folder 12)
    - Correspondence: Durr, Virginia, 1966-1971 (Box 8, Folder 13)
    - Correspondence: Foundations, 1967, 1979, 2003-2004 (Box 8, Folder 14)
    - Correspondence: Harrington, Ollie, Undated (Box 8, Folder 15)
    - Correspondence: Hunton, Alphaeus and Dorothy, 1963 (Box 8, Folder 16)
    - Correspondence: Neel, Alice, 1980 (Box 8, Folder 17)
    - Correspondence: Roosevelt, Franklin Delano, 1944 (Box 8, Folder 18)
    - Correspondence: Salutes to Paul Robeson, 1965-1968, 1972 (Box 8, Folder 19)
    - Correspondence: Schomburg Center for Research in Black Culture, 1997-2004 (Box 8, Folder 20)
    - Correspondence: Seeger, Pete, 1967-1975 (Box 8, Folder 21)
    - Correspondence: Walker, Alice, 1974-1985 (Box 8, Folder 22)
    - Correspondence: Washington, Mary Helen, 1977-2000 (Box 8, Folder 23)
    - Correspondence: The W.E.B. Du Bois Film Project / The W.E.B. Du Bois Foundation, 1995-1996 (Box 8, Folder 24)
    - Correspondence: White, Charles, 1980 (Box 8, Folder 25)
    - Correspondence: White, Evelyn, 1999-2000 (Box 8, Folder 26)
    - Grant Application: Written History of the Southern Negro Youth Congress, titled "Like the Dew They Covered Dixie", 1990 (Box 8, Folder 27)
    - Subseries VII:B: Writings.
      - Interview with Esther Jackson ( Abafazi 9, no. 1, Fall/Winter 1998) (Box 8, Folder 28)
      - Household Employment in Hartford, Waterbury and Litchfield, 1934 (Box 8, Folder 29)
      - A Life in the Whirlwind, 2001-2002 (Box 8, Folder 30)
      - The Negro Woman Domestic Worker in Relation to Trade Unionism - M.A. Thesis for Fisk University, 1940 (Box 8, Folder 31)
      - This is My Husband Reviewed by John Pittman, Undated (Box 8, Folder 32)
      - W.E.B. Du Bois annual Lecture at University of Massachusetts, 2002 (Box 8, Folder 33)
- Series VIII: Lectures.
  - Africa in Strategic Transition: from Decolonization to Social Emancipation, Undated (Box 8, Folder 34)
  - The Bottom Line, Undated (Box 8, Folder 35)
  - Capitalism, Undated (Box 8, Folder 36)
  - Capitalism - What's Wrong With It?, 1981 (Box 8, Folder 37)
  - Capitalism's Ornery Nature: An Economics Teaching from Marxism - Leninism, 1977 (Box 8, Folder 38)
  - The Class Struggle in History, Undated (Box 8, Folder 39)
  - Commodity Production, Undated (Box 8, Folder 40)
  - On the Communist Party, Undated (Box 8, Folder 41)
  - Decade of the 1890's in North Carolina, Undated (Box 8, Folder 42)
  - The Decade of the 1880's in North Carolina, 1978 (Box 8, Folder 43)
  - Dialectical Materialism, Undated (Box 8, Folder 44)
  - Dialectics, 1975 (Box 8, Folder 45)
  - On Education, Undated (Box 8, Folder 46)
  - Excerpts, Undated (Box 8, Folder 47)
  - Falsifiers of Marxism, 1975 (Box 8, Folder 48)
  - Historical Materialism, Undated (Box 8, Folder 49)
  - Historical Materialism, 1975 (Box 8, Folder 50)
  - Historical Materialism, 1976 (Box 8, Folder 51)
  - History of the CPUSA Policy on Afro-American Equality, 1987 (Box 8, Folder 52)
  - The History of the Party's Position on the Struggle for Afro-American Equality and Against Racism" (Tape Transcript), 1987 (Box 8, Folder 53)
  - Importance of the Leading Role of the Working Class and its Marxist-Leninist Party in the Socialist Countries for the Struggle of Working People in the Developed Countries, 1970 (Box 8, Folder 54)
  - Lenin, Undated (Box 8, Folder 55)
  - Maoism, 1975 (Box 8, Folder 56)
  - Martin Luther King, 1976 (Box 8, Folder 57)
  - Marxism-Leninism / Contemporary World Politics (Tape Label: Com. Morality), 1977 (Box 8, Folder 58)
  - Marxism-Leninism / Discussion (Unedited Transcription), Undated (Box 8, Folder 59)
  - Marxism-Leninism / Left Wing Communism (Unedited Transcription), Undated (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - Marxism-Leninism / Philosophy (Unedited Transcription), Undated (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - Marxism-Leninism / Revolutionary Process, Three Components of Revolution, Undated (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - Marxism-Leninism /Strategy and Tactics, Undated (Box 9, Folder 4)
  - Materialism, 1975 (Box 9, Folder 5)
  - Materialism, 1976 (Box 9, Folder 6)
  - National Question, 1975, Undated (Box 9, Folder 7)
  - Nationalization in the U.S., 1976 (Box 9, Folder 8)
  - Nature of Modern Day Capitalism and the Reforms of it's Political Structure, 1976 (Box 9, Folder 9)
  - Notes on lectures written by Jackson, 1972, 1973, Undated (Box 9, Folder 10)
  - Notes on lectures written by others, 1976, 1979, Undated (Box 9, Folder 11)
  - Origin and Development of Man, 1976 (Box 9, Folder 12)
  - The Party, 1981 (Box 9, Folder 13)
  - Party History, 1975 (Box 9, Folder 14)
  - Party Organization, 1976 (Box 9, Folder 15)
  - Party Theory, 1975 (Box 9, Folder 16)
  - Philosophical Falsifiers, 1975 (Box 9, Folder 17)
  - Philosophy, 1977 (Box 9, Folder 18)
  - The Philosophy of Communism, Undated (Box 9, Folder 19)
  - The Philosophy of Communism and the Viewpoint of the Communist Party on Current Questions, 1962 (Box 9, Folder 20)
  - Plan for a Lecture Series on the Political Economy of Capitalism, 1975 (Box 9, Folder 21)
  - Political Economy, Undated (Box 9, Folder 22)
  - Political Economy, 1975 (Box 9, Folder 23)
  - Political Economy, 1976 (Box 9, Folder 24)
  - Political Economy, 1977 (Box 9, Folder 25)
  - Portland, OR, Lecture series: Dialectical Materialism, What is Philosophy? Historical Materialism, The Class Struggle, On Capitalism, On Socialism, On the Communist Party (Cassettes are in the Audiocassettes series), 1978 (Box 9, Folder 26)
  - Q & As, Undated (Box 9, Folder 27)
  - Revolutionary Conditions, 1976 (Box 9, Folder 28)
  - The Scientific - Technological Revolution and the World Revolutionary Process, 1973 (Box 9, Folder 29)
  - Socialism, Undated (Box 9, Folder 30)
  - The Socialist Countries and the Class Struggle in the Capitalist Countries, 1970 (Box 9, Folder 31)
  - The State, 1975 (Box 9, Folder 32)
  - The State and the Nature and Character of Fascism, 1975 (Box 9, Folder 33)
  - Strategy and Tactics, 1975, 1977 (Box 9, Folder 34)
  - Struggle in the South (History of…), 1974 (Box 9, Folder 35)
  - Tape Transcriptions with No Titles, Undated, 1973, 1974-1977 (Box 9, Folder 36)
  - Teaching of Karl Marx for the United States, 1983 (Box 9, Folder 37)
  - Writings of Potemkin and the African Continental Revolution, Plus Additional Remarks, 1976 (Box 9, Folder 38)
  - Woman's Question, 1977 (Box 9, Folder 39)
- Series IX: Notebooks.
  - Notebooks: Chronological / No. 1-5., 1959, 1963, 1972-1978 (Box 9, Folder 40)
  - Notebooks: Chronological / No. 6-11., 1980-1985 (Box 9, Folder 41)
  - Notebooks: Chronological / No. 12-18., 1986-1991 (Box 9, Folder 42)
  - Notebooks: No. 19-23, Russian Lessons, Undated (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - Notebooks: No. 24-26, Vietnam, Undated (Box 10, Folder 2)
  - Notebooks: No. 27-37, Undated (Box 10, Folder 3)
  - Notebooks: 38-46, Undated (Box 10, Folder 4)
  - Notebooks: 47-56, Undated (Box 10, Folder 5)
  - Notebooks: 57-65, Undated (Box 10, Folder 6)
  - Notebooks: No. 66-78, Undated (Box 10, Folder 7)
  - Notebooks: No. 79-86, Undated (Box 10, Folder 8)
  - Notebooks: Excerpts, Undated (Box 10, Folder 9)
- Series X: Smith Act.
  - Appellee's Brief, Undated (Box 11, Folder 1)
  - Charney, George Blake, Notice of Motion, 1956 (Box 11, Folder 2)
  - Clippings, 1946-1962 (Box 11, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence, 1936, 1952-1957 (Box 11, Folder 4)
  - CPUSA International Affairs, Undated (Box 11, Folder 5)
  - Crockett, George; Winter, Carl, 1949 (Box 11, Folder 6)
  - Davis, Benjamin J., 1954 (Box 11, Folder 7)
  - Du Bois, W.E.B.: Testimony, 1956 (Box 11, Folder 8)
  - James Jackson Defense Committee, 1956-1963 (Box 11, Folder 9)
  - Jackson, James E.: Notes, Undated (Box 11, Folder 10)
  - Jackson, James E.: Statement Before Sentencing, 1956 (Box 11, Folder 11)
  - Jackson, James E., Sr. Testimony, Undated (Box 11, Folder 12)
  - Legal Documents, 1956-1958 (Box 11, Folder 13)
  - "Testimony: from Anonymous African-American Activist re his Being Interviewed by FBI in 1951", Undated (Box 11, Folder 14)
- Series XI: Southern Negro Youth Congress.
  - Articles, Notes, 1977, 1987, Undated (Box 11, Folder 15)
  - Civil Rights Activity, Undated (Box 11, Folder 16)
  - Clippings, Pictorial, Undated (Box 11, Folder 17)
  - Constitution, Undated (Box 11, Folder 18)
  - Correspondence, Undated (Box 11, Folder 19)
  - Correspondence, 1937-1945 (Box 11, Folder 20)
  - Correspondence, 1946-1949 (Box 11, Folder 21)
  - Correspondence: Academia (Richards, Johnetta), 1975-1979 (Box 11, Folder 22)
  - Correspondence: E.D. Nixon; Thurgood Marshall Letters, 1944-1945 (Box 11, Folder 23)
  - Documents, Publications, Clippings, Undated (Box 11, Folder 24)
  - Documents, Publications, Clippings, 1937 (Box 11, Folder 25)
  - Documents, Publications, Clippings, 1938 (Box 11, Folder 26)
  - Documents, Publications, Clippings, 1939 (Box 11, Folder 27)
  - Documents, Publications, Clippings, 1940 (Box 11, Folder 28)
  - Documents, Publications, Clippings, 1941 (Box 11, Folder 29)
  - Documents, Publications, Clippings, 1942 (Box 11, Folder 30)
  - Documents, Publications, Clippings, 1943 (Box 11, Folder 31)
  - Documents, Publications, Clippings, 1944 (Box 11, Folder 32)
  - Documents, Publications, Clippings, 1945 (Box 11, Folder 33)
  - Documents, Publications, Clippings, 1946 (Box 11, Folder 34)
  - Documents, Publications, Clippings, 1947 (Box 11, Folder 35)
  - Documents, Publications, Clippings, 1948 (Box 11, Folder 36)
  - FBI FOIA Files (requested by Robin Kelley), 1 of 2, Undated (Box 12, Folder 1)
  - FBI FOIA Files (requested by Robin Kelley), 2 of 2, Undated (Box 12, Folder 1A)
  - Florida, 1945, 1947 (Box 12, Folder 2)
  - Interview with James Jackson (Shapiro, Linn), Oct 1992 (Box 12, Folder 3)
  - Manual of Organization, ca.1945-1996 (Box 12, Folder 4)
  - Southern African-American Contact List, 1930s-1940s (Box 12, Folder 5)